Unknown calls?
Promising lottery and money?
अनजान कॉल्स?
लॉटरी और पैसे का वादा?


Save yourself some time.
Save yourself from fraud.
खुद के लिए कुछ समय बचाएं।
खुद को धोखाधड़ी से बचाएं।


Avoid responding to a call promising prizes, lottery, and gifts as fraudsters can make you deposit a huge amount of money either as a money transfer fee, payment of taxes, or transportation cost.
इनाम, लॉटरी और उपहारों का वादा करनेवाले कॉल को उत्तर देने से बचें क्योंकि जालसाज आपसे पैसे हस्तांतरण शुल्क, करों का भुगतान, या परिवहन की लागत के रूप में एक बड़ी राशि जमा करवा सकते हैं।

How to avoid falling into the fraudulent caller trap
जालसाज कॉलर के जाल में फंसने से कैसे बचें

Do not speak with the caller asking for crucial information, ignore such calls.
आपसे फोन पर महत्त्वपूर्ण जानकारी मांगने वाले व्यक्ती से बात ना करें, ऐसे फोन काट दें।

Block unknown phone numbers which prompt for personal and financial information without reason.
बिना किसी वजह व्यक्तिगत और वित्तीय जानकारी पूछने वाले अनजान फोन नंबर को ब्लॉक करें।

Only use details from RBL Bank official website i.e. www.rblbank.com to find contact details of support center.
सहायता केंद्र के संपर्क की जानकारी ढूंढने के लिए सिर्फ आरबीएल बैंक की आधिकारिक वेबसाइट www.rblbank.com पर मौजूद विवरण का उपयोग करें।

RBL Bank will never ask for personal details such as your PAN No., Credit Card No., CVV, Card Expiry Date, OTP, MyCard App, MPIN, etc.
आरबीएल बैंक कभी भी आपसे आपका पैन नंबर, क्रेडिट कार्ड नंबर, सीवीवी, कार्ड एक्सपायरी तिथि, ओटीपी, माईकार्ड एप, एमपिन आदि जैसी व्यक्तिगत जानकारी नही मांगेगा।
